<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Between The Lobes</title>
    <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Between The Lobes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://betweenthelobes.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Posters</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/research-portfolio/posters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/research-portfolio/posters/</guid>
      <description>Society for Neuroscience 2019
Society for Affective Science 2018
Armadillo 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/research-portfolio/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/research-portfolio/slides/</guid>
      <description>May 2022
February 2021
February 2020
March 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV &#43; Resume</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/research-portfolio/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/research-portfolio/cv/</guid>
      <description>CV
Resume</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/about-me/</guid>
      <description>My name is Lauryn Burleigh. I prefer to go by L or Burleigh and use any pronoun. I am the creator of the Between The Lobes site. I’m a big animal person. I have a Border-Collie/Lab mix named Roxy and an American Pitbull Terrier named Bronson, an American Staffordshire Terrier named Tina, and a bearded dragon named Severus. I also have two rabbits, Cal and Moo.
I began my graduate career in Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Nidra and Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/nidra-mentalhealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/nidra-mentalhealth/</guid>
      <description>Yoga Nidra is a specific type of yoga that focuses on inducing total relaxation. Though it includes relaxing physically, Yoga Nidra emphasizes mental and emotional relaxation and well-being. There are very few asanas (physical yoga poses) in a Yoga Nidra class. I generally describe Yoga Nidra as a guided meditation. There are multiple types of readings that can be done in Nidra classes, including readings that focus on the breath, the body, visualizations, emotions, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga&#39;s Effects on Sleep</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/yoga-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/yoga-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Sleep is essential for the well-being and overall health of humans, both in the short and long-term (Fox, 1999). It impacts cognitive functioning in many areas including short term memory, working memory, and increased communication between regions in the brain (Chee, 2008). Sleep deprivation has also been linked to increased cortisol, the stress hormone, and increased stress related pathways. Weight gain, insulin production, and diabetes can also be impacted by a lack of sleep (Hirotsu, 2015).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotion Awareness</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/emotion-awareness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/emotion-awareness/</guid>
      <description>Pratyahara, one of yoga’s 8 limbs (guidelines to a meaningful and purposeful life), is withdrawal. In this limb, the goal is to draw the senses and awareness inward, and away from the external world. This practice focuses on awareness of oneself and maintaining inner awareness. Having an awareness of one’s thoughts and emotions increases their emotion regulation abilities (Gross, 1998).
Emotion regulation is the process of actively influencing the emotions we have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meditation and Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/meditation-and-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/meditation-and-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>Major depression and anxiety disorders are among the most common lifetime diagnoses. In 2005, 33.3% of Americans had a diagnosis of major depression and 30.3% had an anxiety disorder (Pilkington et al., 2005). These numbers are also rising, and do not include individuals who suffer from these disorders but do not receive help or a diagnosis, an estimated 50% of individuals (Tonks, 2003).
Kozasa et al., 2008 studied the effects of Siddha Samadhi Yoga on anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga and Brain Waves</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/yoga-and-brain-waves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/yoga-and-brain-waves/</guid>
      <description>An Electroencephalogram (EEG) is a cap with electrodes that is placed on the head that record brain waves. While this data does not indicate where in the brain a process is occurring, it indicates when a process is occurring. These time sensitive waves allow scientists to further understand cognitive processes.
Multiple EEG studies were used to investigate the effects of yoga on brain waves. Desai et al. (cited below) completed a review of these studies, which together help explain the decrease of anxiety and the increase of focus experienced after yoga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pranayama and the Nervous System</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/pranayama-and-the-nervous-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/science-and-yoga/pranayama-and-the-nervous-system/</guid>
      <description>Pranayama is a conscious breathing movement in which inhales and exhales are slowed and controlled. Pranayama accompanies asanas, or poses, in Vinyasa yoga. Pranayama usually occurs in 3 stages: inhale, retention (holding the breath), and exhale. In a vinyasa yoga session, each movement is purposefully accompanied with one or more of these stages.
Pranayama and slow breathing exercises have been found to decrease heart rate (Pal &amp;amp; Velkumary (2004), Bhargava, Gogate, &amp;amp; Mascarenhas (1988)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Produce Functional Activation within Anatomical Mask- fMRI</title>
      <link>https://betweenthelobes.com/tutorials/create-functional-activation-within-anatomical-mask-fmri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://betweenthelobes.com/tutorials/create-functional-activation-within-anatomical-mask-fmri/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will demonstrate how to create a mask of the functional activation within a region of interest. I used fsl and Ubuntu for this tutorial.
For each step (especially the first time creating a mask) it is suggested to open and quality check within fslview.
Open Group level activation for condition desired in fslviewthresh_zstat#.nii.gzOpen on top of bg_image.nii.gzAdd atlas in fslviewTools –&amp;gt; Toolbars –&amp;gt; Atlas ToolsAdd structures desired from atlasClick Structures… (under Atlas Tools box at bottom)Choose AtlasCerebellar Atlas in MNI152 space after normalization with FNIRTChoose Structures desiredPress “+” to add to Overlay SettingsPress Ok to close window when done choosing structuresThe structures chosen will appear on the image and in the Overlay Settings box.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>